[Music]
good evening and good day everyone
welcome to episode 15 of ask abidjit
i hope you are doing great on this fine
sunday evening
or morning or day wherever you are so
before i begin
i'd like to let you know that i have
started uploading short clips
on this channel i had earlier made a
separate channel for short clips but i
think no one was able to find that
so just for the sake of everyone's
convenience i am uploading them
to this channel i have made a separate
playlist for the short clips
and a separate playlist for these longer
videos so
it's all well organized so i hope that
will offer you more convenience and
you'll be able to find
individual answers to questions that
you're looking for
so i hope that helps and i'm gonna
continue uploading these clips
on a regular basis so today we're gonna
discuss
indian history i think it's everyone's
favorite topic
and as always i have a bucket load of
questions
so let's get right into it with question
number one
so this is by harshit panth do you think
a full-blown civil war
in 1947 would have been far better
a far better option than the creation of
pakistan and the subsequent wars rifts
riots etc that we have had that's a
great question so how do we approach
this issue do we have any historical
precedents
so so think about it this way
in the united states they've had a lot
of presidents right
and they don't have any official father
of the nation kind of figure
but the one person who comes closest to
the father of the nation for the
american people
is abraham lincoln and he is also
considered to be
their greatest president he is the one
person i mean u.s presidents have known
are known to have done all kinds of
nasty things but among all of the us
presidents he's
the one person who is reputed as a as a
person of great integrity
he's the one who comes closest to being
a saint
so i'm talking about abraham lincoln
over here
so in 1861
abraham lincoln was faced with the same
question
partition or civil war the same option
that mohandas gandhi had
in the 1940s and what option did
so what happened was that the southern
states
in the united states has had seceded
from the nation
they had declared their independence so
the united states
was was basically on the brink of a de
facto partition
that's what was happening so abraham
lincoln had two options
either allow the partition to happen
allow the south to go its own way
or go to war and have a civil war in the
united states
and what option did he take he chose to
go to war
the civil war happened under his watch
correct and we know the history the the
north one they were able to uh retain a
united
united states they were they were able
to prevent the fragmentation of the
nation
and history would have been very
different if abraham lincoln had allowed
the country to be partitioned right
so it is because of these actions and
these decisions that he took
and the decision to the very difficult
decision to go to war
it is because of all of these actions of
his that he is regarded as the greatest
president and
he's regarded almost as a saint and in
some way as
a de facto father of the nation if
anyone can come close to the title in
the u.s
now in india we consider muhammad gandhi
to be the father of the nation
but he's actually the father of pakistan
he allowed
the fragmentation of india he oversaw
the fragmentation of india he kept
saying that partition will happen over
my dead body
but he his words went in one direction
his actions went in the opposite
direction
he facilitated the partition of india he
did nothing
to prevent the partition of india words
and actions
are meaningless it's only a words and
words are meaningless slogans are
meaningless your actions are the only
thing that matter
and action can also be a lack of action
in the
as in the case of mohandas gandhi so we
had the partition of india
without consulting the people of india
it was never put to a vote there was
never a referendum
there was no constitution of india at
the time which would prefer which would
prevent a referendum
so there would there was definitely the
option of go
of having a referendum and asking the
people of india whether they wanted
whether they were willing to give up
land their ancestral land
which has been part of india for
thousands of years
so the democratic option was never
exercised mohandas gandhi did not
believe in democracy
and the country was broken up and what
happened next is
we know what happened we have been at
war with pakistan ever since
it's sometimes an open war sometimes an
undeclared war
usually it's proxy warfare and terrorism
from from pakistan side
and india just sits there and takes it
and now the
war i mean the both sides both sides
have nuclear weapons so it's a
nuclear-armed civil war essentially
so this is a continuation of the civil
war
gandhi said that i want to prevent
violence well to prevent violence in 47
he ensured there will be violence until
2020 and
further so i think that there are times
when there are just causes for warfare
there are times when violence
is called for in the mahabharata lord
krishna tried his best to negotiate a
settlement
and prevent the war and when everything
failed
he exhorted arjuna and both and and his
side
to go to war this is just what forget
about
everything that happened in the past you
have to do what you have to do
just do your duty that's it so that's
the thing i mean
this this uh this obsession with
averting violence at all costs itself is
a form of greater violence
because it it it prolongs the conflict
over an extended period of time people
who are not born in 1947
are still bearing the brunt of mohandas
gandhi's actions and the actions of
other people in the in the
so-called indian independence movement
the so-called leaders
so whom did these people really serve is
the question
we know that the british wanted to
fragment india it was on their agenda
jinnah was just a pawn and so was
mohandas gandhi who was a larger pawn
so the partition is what the british
wanted
they knew that they had to leave india
anyway there was nothing left to extract
from india india was
destitute it was impoverished all the
wealth had been extracted away
the british did not want to govern a
country that was in such shambles which
they had
brought into such shambles so they
wanted an exit strategy
and the exit strategy was to break india
up into pieces and then play the pieces
against one other one another
so that they it will give them a
geopolitical advantage in
the gulf region in which they still had
substantial interest because of oil
and because of the because we know that
there was so much
oil over there and they wanted to keep
extracting that and keep benefiting from
from that
and they also had substantial
possessions
in the middle east at the time so they
wanted
india and party india and pakistan to be
partitioned they wanted the pakistanis
to be
beholden to the british so that they
would keep
playing a geopolitical role in britain's
favor if india had been uh had been
allowed to remain undivided it would
have been antagonistic to the british
most conceivably
under a united leadership so they
ensured that they
transferred power to people of their
choice
india's independence india's first prime
minister was not elected he was selected
right mr uh the great great shari
jawal nehru so this is what happened
independence was actually not it was a
transfer of power from one set of crooks
to another set of crooks
and and so that's the answer would a
full-blown civil war in 47 have been
better
conceivably yes finish it off once and
for all
right whatever issues are left behind
from the tumultuous history of partition
of of the british occupation and the
previous turkic occupation all that
deal with it once and for all and move
on after that instead of prolonging it
and
moving it forward slice by slice cut by
cut blow by blow
as it's happening right now so this
matter is still unresolved
this so-called violence that gandhi
hoped to avert
it's still going on it has taken the
form of at least
four major wars and so much bloodshed
that
has happened because of proxy warfare
and whatnot
in the pakistani occupation of
balochistan and kashmir
parts of kashmir and parts of the
pashtun territories and sindh
it's brutal it's oppressive and this is
what the british engineered and this is
what
the so-called great leaders of india's
independence movement
facilitated so i think it would have
been better
for india to have dealt with the matter
once and for all in 1947 instead of
prolonging it
unnecessarily and pointlessly like
it's been done right now good question
sir
okay yashvardhan asks please tell us
about the kalash people of
kafiristan or so called nuristan their
culture and their heroic
resistance so let me show you who these
kalash people are
the kalash people they are one second
one second let me pull up the particular
web page
so that i can share it with you
okay so this is the google search for
the kalash people the college people are
an ancient
indigenous people of north western india
which is present-day
northwestern pakistan region in parts of
afghanistan
the region of pakistan is called chitral
it is west of gilgit balthastan
pakistan occupied gilgit pakistan and
the region of afghanistan is present-day
nuristan
they call it nuristan now it was earlier
called kaphiristan
because these people held on to their
ancient beliefs
and when it was sanitized and the
ancient beliefs were stamped out it was
called nuristan the land of light
so these are the people of of uh the
kalash people
as you can see they look mostly uh they
look more like europeans in some way you
know they have a european kind of
appearance and somehow all most of the
images are of
uh or of women females
and they have very nice interesting
dresses and all
these are clearly non-muslims these
people practice
a very ancient form of hinduism it's
almost like a rigvedic
form of hinduism very very ancient
and so these are the people they have
they're a very small group
in this region it is it is a bunch like
about three or four valleys in the high
mountains
in this region and because they are so
isolated that's why they have been
able to uh to
escape the the brutality of the foreign
occupation
and they have been able to thus far to
some extent preserve the culture
they they basically were massacred in
afghanistan
and kapharistan was turned into nuristan
which means they were all converted by
force whoever survived
and now the same thing is happening in
chitral in pakistan
so these taliban is people they are they
are basically
converting them by force so these are
the ancient people
or they who who are these people
basically
so their genetic if you their dna has
been analyzed
so what is found is that their
patrilineal dna lineages are
all of indian subcontinent origin
r1a etc these are all indian lineages
they are mostly found
in extremely high proportions and
frequencies and diversity
in the indian subcontinent but the
matrilineal lineages seem to be of
western eurasian
origin so it looks like that ancestral
maternal populations
were possibly of western eurasian origin
so it's a very interesting
mixture of genetics over here so the
matrilineal lineages are of western
eurasian origin to to a large extent not
fully
and the petroleum lineages are indian
and the culture is in is an ancient form
of hinduism
so it's clear that they have been
isolated and they've been practicing
this this culture for a very long time
for several thousand years
some of them nowadays believe that they
are the descendants of greek soldiers of
alexander etc
uh dna analysis shows that this is just
a myth it's just a belief
there is no dna evidence that in any way
bears that out
so these are essentially an ancient
indian group
with some of basically female foreign
lineages
western eurasian lineages that also in
antiquity might have been indian in
origin because as you know
indians have been getting going
westwards out of india for
nearly 10 000 years so it's a very
interesting population they still to
some extent
uh practice their original culture
their indigenous culture but uh
in recent times in the past two or three
decades the the forced conversions have
been intensifying the
the frequency is increasing and it looks
like this beautiful ancient
culture may not last for a very long
time
so that is the truth about the kalash
people that's who they are it's a
it's a sad story it's a tragic story uh
it looks like they may soon get
assimilated into the
mainstream pakistani population and
culture i hope that doesn't happen
i hope that they're able to continue i
mean
the world is beautiful when there's so
much diversity a mono culture is
dull boring and insipid you want
diversity of cultures and traditions and
beliefs and that's what makes the world
interesting
you go to a new place there's something
new to see every time instead of seeing
the same old same old everywhere
so i hope that this very interesting and
very beautiful
ancient culture survives i hope it is
preserved
but the future doesn't look that great
for them so that's who the kalash people
are they are an ancient
indo well indo-european people mostly of
indian origin but their matrilineal
lineages seem to be
of western eurasian origin which is very
interesting
there's a story behind that which has
not yet been discovered so
there's uh there's more to there's more
to know
in the case of these people
okay akash asks what are some overlooked
facts about the life
of ashok is his conversion to buddhism
overrated
okay that's an interesting question so
ashok the great we are taught that ashok
was this great
great king he is given this title of the
great
uh the third mauryan uh
emperor the great conqueror of kalinga
etc
the great pacifist who destroyed kalinga
and killed so many people and then
was overcome with remorse because his
hinduism made him
kill so many people and that's why he
converted to buddhism and became a saint
and then he spread all these
inscriptions throughout
the the land the length and the breadth
of india saying that i am a great man
and i am i believe in buddhism and i
have
i i believe in pacifism and all that and
the inscriptions are found throughout
india
even afghanistan pakistan present day
right
so that's the story that's the story
that our historians have been telling us
that he rejected hinduism and converted
to buddhism after he destroyed
kalinga and saw the slaughter which he
attributed to hinduism
what is the truth well firstly
there is zero evidence that he can see
first of all there's no conversion to
hinduism or buddhism
if you start practicing buddhist
philosophy
and practices in daily life you are a
buddhist there's no conversion process
right
you're not dunked into a into a tub of
water or anything to to be converted
there's no conversion
so the thing is ashok is known to have
embraced
the precepts of buddhism at some point
in his life and there is
zero factual evidence textual evidence
or any evidence
that this happened after the kalinga war
it is actually most likely from the
evidence that we have from all the
evidence that the
so-called indian historians present the
same evidence
actually points to the fact that he
embraced the
tenets of buddhism before the so-called
kalinga war happened right that's point
number one
so the the overwhelming evidence tells
us that he
became a practicing buddhist
he became he started he embraced both
the dharma before the kalinga war itself
and what we know about ashok's
the beginnings of his life so he was the
uh
he was one of the sons of bindu sir
bindu was the second morning ambassador
oh sorry
maureen emperor bindu sir was the son
of chandragupta mori the first mauryan
emperor
and the crown prince
during ashok's time was his half-brother
another son of bindu sir with a
different wife
now this half brother was in the
northwest of india
the boundaries the western boundaries of
afghanistan fighting off some invaders
greeks or scythians or whatever
and that's when bindu sir happened to
die so the crown prince rushed back to
partly putra which was the then present
the then capital of the of india
and he found that his brother ashok had
taken over the throne and ashok had this
half brother
killed his own half brother he had him
killed
he killed many of his other siblings to
consolidate his grip on the throne it's
almost like an ottoman slaughter in
which the or when an ottoman
sultan would be enthroned he would
immediately on the same day kill all of
his brothers and our brothers
to ensure that there is no threat to his
crown so that's the kind of
slaughter ashok perpetrated it is
recorded that he had about 99 of his
siblings
killed brothers half brothers etc
i think he spared only one of his
brothers right
and it seems that uh so at the time
india was a very eclectic culture there
were so many different
parts of dharma different schools of
thought you had the ajivikas you had the
jains you had the
the both the dharma you had the
mainstream
forms of dharma which we now call
hinduism
and we had different philosophies and
paths the charvakas were present and
many others right
so it seems that when ashok consol was
consolidating
his his grip on the throne the jainas
and the ajivikas who may have had ties
with
other family members of his who he
killed they kind of
resisted what he was doing and therefore
he embarked upon a vicious
persecution of the jaina and the aji
people
the people who followed those
philosophical parts of
of dharma of hinduism right
so that's why he went on this rampage
it seems that he had many thousands of
ajivikas killed
he even persecuted the jains and this is
not religious persecution
this is because these people had opposed
him coming to the throne in the manner
that he did so this is a form of
persecution
nowadays the marxist historians call
this religious persecution because
at the time ashok was a hindu but at the
time he had already embraced
the tenets of buddhism by the way so he
did all of this
while being a buddhist all right and he
went to war with kalinga he
invaded kalinga and wiped basically the
entire kalinga rb out
as a buddhist at least a hundred
thousand one lakh
kalingan soldiers were massacred in that
in the
battle which was a route and at least
1.5
lakh prisoners were taken
so it seemed that kalinga at the time
was actually a
vasal state or a province of the mauryan
empire
i mean the mauryan empire was so large
and it was an expansionist empire it
went beyond
present-day india way beyond present-day
india so it is inconceived
inconceivable that kalinga right next
door to parliament would have been an
independent state it would not have been
allowed to be so so kalinga at the time
was most likely
a vasal state or a province of the
mauryan empire and maybe
when ashok came to power and in the way
he did maybe they tried to rebel against
him or they opposed him
and maybe that's why he went to war with
kalinga we don't know who was the king
of kalinga at the time i
still haven't been able to find the name
of the of the king but i'll try and do
that
so basically the truth is that he was a
vicious and
very cruel person ashok is he was known
as chanda ashok means a really evil
ashok
right so he he is exactly the opposite
of how he's portrayed he's portrayed as
a pacifist and a saintly person
he was a vicious mass murderer that's
what he was
and he put up all these pillars and
inscriptions talking about pacifism
but he did not put any pillar advocating
passive pacifism
in the region of kalinga or partly patra
the pacifistic pillars and all the
inscriptions were put
in the far west of india in present day
afghanistan etc
so that's the kind of person he was it
was just a political statement
politicians say all kinds of things to
to appear nice and that's precisely what
ashok was doing
so firstly he was not a hindu
so-called hindu when he went to war with
kalinga he was already a practicing
buddhist
and secondly he was not a pacifist he
was one of the
most vicious kings of india so
everything we know we have been
everything we've been taught about him
is a lie so this is the ncrt textbooks
at work
it is only after the indian independence
when uh well when a certain political
ideology was adopted in india in a
certain
uh there was this desire to downplay
hinduism and
uh you know and uh show that other
faiths are better etc
so that's when all these stories were
concocted and placed in our textbooks
and that's what we've been learning so
far
even i for most of my life believe that
ashok was the great guy you know
he he came to power and he went to war
and then he had this change of heart and
became buddhist
and that's the story the truth is very
different he was a practicing buddhist
while he did all this
so twist in the tail my friends
all right this is a long question by
pritish
pai was it a good thing that india was
colonized by the british my arguments
british were less brutal marginally less
brittle than space spanish or belgians
being a colony saved us from being a
diver direct rival of other powers
being in the british kept us under low
profile a strong india would have kept
created a separate poll to crush this
non-violent civilizations would have
etc and our colonial legacy the english
language is the blessing
in disguise as it is the global language
of technology and culture
this may prove to be our greatest
strength in exporting our culture to the
rest of the world
so pritish i i i respect what you say
this is what many many people believe
that's what many people i know
believe this you know so i
i have a different viewpoint so let me
uh
invite you to understand that let me
offer my viewpoint to this
i disagree with the arguments that you
have presented so let me explain
why i disagree so
um see all colonizers
are brutal whether it's the spanish or
the belgians or the british
i mean the british killed more than 100
million
indians in artificially engineered
famines
i don't think the spanish have been that
brutal anywhere
i don't think the belgians have been
that brutal they killed about 10 million
people in the congo in about a few a few
decades
but the way the british
killed so many indians in artificially
engineered famines
and these this this figure of 10 million
it's just basically
british figures the actual figures may
have been much much higher
so people say that they don't believe
when i say that the british killed
10 million people so let me let me just
briefly show you a timeline of famines
in india this is
from wikipedia first of all please
understand that i do not
support wikipedia i don't advocate
wikipedia as a reliable source wikipedia
is very problematic
i'm just showing it in wikipedia for the
sake of convenience and time
so you can see how many famines were
there in india 1979 two to
10 million 1783 11 million
11 here one here two million here one
million here
one and a half million here uh something
else here five and a half million here
five million here
etc 4.5 million there 1.5 million here
and that's just a few and these are all
grossly underestimated figures
they don't first of all include the
numbers who died from epidemics
because of the malnutrition and all that
and these numbers are
grossly under underestimated because
these are british figures you cannot
rely on british figures you cannot rely
on the figures given you
given to you by your occupiers okay so
they killed
at least 100 million people just by
starving them to death
slowly systematically bureaucratically
and they killed
more than 10 million people in the
immediate aftermath of 1857 the first
war of independence their brutality was
unmatched
and unparalleled okay so we can't say
that the british were less brutal
marginally or otherwise
than any other occupier than any other
colonialist all colonialists are the
same
they they they don't care about anyone's
human rights
so that's the first thing a strong india
india would have created a separate poll
a strong india is what is required if
you are weak you are invisible but
that's not good
right if you are strong you will have
enemies that's the that's
that comes with the territory of being
strong we must be strong
if you're strong you will have enemies
and you need to know how to deal with
that
that is called being strong if you are
economically powerful but you don't have
a military then you are not strong and
you are inviting
big big trouble so it is for a country a
civilization of india's size and
magnitudes it is
imperative it is essential it is i mean
you have to be strong
okay there there is no other alternative
to being strong
india has to be strong separate poll
crush this non-vedic civilizations
if you're strong enough no one can crush
you so once again i
can't agree with that our colonial
legacy india's uh
the english language is a blessing in
disguise we will export indian culture
sanskrit
so look i'm not trying to make fun of
you or to uh or that you know
my point is that okay
let me show you some some data right see
if english is such a big advantage
and why do facts bear something else out
so let me show you some some statistics
right
okay let me get rid of the question so
these are
the statistics of the top 10 countries
in the world
by nominal gdp these are the top top 10
largest economies in the world the
united states china japan germany india
uk france italy brazil canada
out of this the united states the uk
and canada are english-speaking
countries
look at the other countries china
they don't use the english language
their education system is in chinese
japan the world's most technologically
advanced country
doesn't use english it offers education
only in japanese
the japanese language has not prevented
them
from becoming the number one
technologically advanced nation in the
world
germany one of the most industrialized
nations and one of the most
technological
advanced nations again they don't use
english they use the german language in
education
in and in everything france i mean come
on
the french will never ever use english
it did not prevent them from building
this
brilliant technology the rafale planes
the nuclear reactors and
much more technology right italy doesn't
use english once again technologically
advanced brazil
not so advanced but still has some
self-respect doesn't use english
and look at of all these countries the
gdp per capita
whose is the lowest it is india with its
english advantage whose gdp per capita
is the lowest
and and it doesn't this this list
doesn't even include russia which is so
advanced
in the in terms of technology and
science they don't use english
they use russian so does english confer
any kind of advantage
let's say myth and and about english
being a language of
culture the english language my friends
does not even have its own script the
english language does not even
have its own written script its own
alphabet it uses the latin
script do you realize that
the script the alphabet that's used to
write the english language
is a foreign alphabet it's the latin
alphabet
and it's it's this it's the one alphabet
that's been imposed upon most of europe
so that's the uh that's the kind of
poverty that you find in the english
language it's not
in any way a superior language it's an
inferior language
sanskrit is the most advanced language
sanskrit is the language of culture
okay and it's also the language of
technology india would never have
i mean india did not have english in the
harappan era
and yet it was the most technologically
and scientifically advanced civilization
in the history of humanity at the time
our
ancient mathematicians our ancient
scientists brahma gupta
and so many more did they use english to
develop
differential calculus integrity
trigonometry and much more
did they use english to develop
astronomy and all the sciences and all
the technology
it was all done with sanskrit so we need
to get over
this mental colonization that all of us
have including me too
i'm talking to you in english so we need
to
find ways of getting over this english
does not provide us with
any advantage it actually hampers us it
keeps us back
we are forced to converse in english
right now because half the country can't
even speak
hindi and hindi is something i'll come
to later on in this program
so my respectful uh
invitation to everyone is please
try and think differently english does
not provide any advantage
the british colonialism was in no way
great for us or good for us
they did not come here to to uplift us
from our from our from our backwardness
we were not backward when they came here
we were backward when they left
they were import impoverished and
destroyed as a nation when they left
they came here
because there was something to take from
here right
so and and the british occupation of
india i mean people say that the british
gave us so much
they gave us so much they gave us
railways for the sake of the gods
railways and ports and roads and
infrastructure and wonderful
buildings and the judiciary for good for
good god
all of that why did they create the
railways
the railways were the infrastructure of
occupation and extraction
they built railways so that they could
extract wealth out of india
they built ports so that they could have
ships come and dock over here
take goods from the railways and get out
and take away our wealth
and these ports and roads and railways
were built with indian money using
indian labor
it was built with wealth extracted out
of india
it was built with slave labor taken from
indians
right please please try and see things
in the proper context
the judiciary they created
was basically for their own benefit it
treated
indians like second-class citizens
indians did not get
the same treatment as british in the in
the british judiciary and
it's interesting to note that it's the
same judiciary that's still there today
nothing has changed in the structure and
the functioning
of the judiciary in the architecture
internal architecture of the judiciary
it's the same institution it's the same
institutions
that we are still carrying forward today
it's it's the same laws
that the british wrote that are still
ruling us
so india needs to decolonize it it's
high time india decolonizes
and we cannot deconalize unless we
realize how deeply colonized we are
so i urge you i invite you all to think
deeply about this and try and try and
figure out the different ways in which
we are colonized because
india is still a very much a colonized
country so first we have to realize it
if you want to
break free from those self-imposed
shackles
aditya asks why is the bengal famine a
massacre done by the british not much
talked about
while the german concentration camps are
criticized
like anything first of all uh
if the germans had won there would have
been no talk of the concentration camps
they would never have existed
secondly why are the german
concentration camps
the nazi concentration camps so
criticized so much
because the americans who defeated the
germans
uh made sure this is widely publicized
so that it gave them the moral
superiority over the germans
because the americans also did terrible
war crimes
during the second world war i mean war
is a time in which you do
terrible acts and when you bombard
civilian populations
that's a war crime the americans did
plenty of that the fire bombing of
dresden good
god it was an atrocity anyhow the
americans insured
and the americans and the british and
the french all the allies
they ensured that this gets a great deal
of
coverage in the press and the media
everywhere
and rightfully so the germans were
monstrous for what they did
for the way they treated the the the
romani and the jewish people
terrible terrible i mean they tried to
wipe these people out from
from existence from the face of the
earth
so it is very rightfully criticized and
the
nazis are very rightfully vilified
for what they did they were absolute
monsters and
that is something that can never be
forgot forgotten or forgiven
now why are the even larger massacres
than by the british not talked about
like i showed you just now there was
famine after famine these were all
artificially engineered famines
and at least a million a hundred million
indians that's
10 crores at least at the very very
minimum
at a conservative estimate were killed
by the british
in these artificial famines this is a
this is at least an order of magnitude
worse than what the germans did
this is a war this is a crime against
humanity by any measure
by by any definition and still we don't
talk about it
and and the latest the last famine they
did before the left was the
uh great bengal famine in which they say
about a million and a half people died
i think the actual figure is near near
six or seven or ten million
but the but we will use the official
british figures
to to count it the actual number i think
is near 10 million
that's how many bengalis died winston
churchill
deliberately starved the bengalis
or i mean all the resources were
available food grains everything
he had them shipped off to europe to aid
the
to supposedly aid the war effort the
second world war effort because
the greeks and other people were
fighting and the indians were just
sitting around
so he deliberately starved the bengalis
and our great mr muhammad as gandhi did
not say a word about it
so the point is the british atrocities
these crimes against humanities are not
talked about because a our historians
don't talk about it
b our media doesn't talk about it and c
because we are not aware of it
so unless we start talking about this in
the open in public
unless we start writing about it unless
our media and other
media channels etc start talking about
it
unless our historians publish books
about this and unless
we make a big deal out of it unless we
publicize this
vigorously this will not be talked about
the west knows about what it's done the
atrocities
and and crimes of the west are
unimaginable and
unimaginable what they did in africa
what they did in north america what did
in south america
and what they did in india and other
parts of asia
i mean if you put if you add up the
death toll it will
exceed a billion and you think it's
ridiculous no it did not happen in one
week or one year
it happened over centuries so over
centuries
if you add up the death toll it will
easily exceed a billion humans
so this is the price that colonialism
extracted
from humanity and this squarely lies on
the west
that's what they did to the to the rest
of the world
so they know what they have done and it
is best for them that these things
remain suppressed
so they will never talk about it the
historians won't speak about it if
if nowadays if there is this change this
woke culture coming in
then some aspects maybe this may be
discussed briefly
but they will not make a big human cry
about it so it is for
us to start discussing discussing these
things it is for us to start writing
about these things
it is for our historians if new
historians were to emerge to write about
this because the existing historians are
all
stooges of colonialism so that's the
reason why these
uh these incredible crimes against
humanity are not spoken about
abhishek asks uh did ancient hindus
eat non-vegetarian food did they eat
meat
if no when did we start eating it etc
ancient
there is nothing against hinduism that
says that you cannot eat meat
it does we do have the uh
principle that ahimsa parma dharma which
means that ahinsa is the is the highest
morality
so which means that it in an ideal
situation you should not kill you should
not eat meat etc
but in the real world you are permitted
to eat meat
especially the people who went to war in
the in historical times even today
the so-called warrior people they
they always eat meat right they've
always been known to eat meat
we have this episode in the ramayana one
of the we have two epics the ramen and
the mahabharata
the ramen is much more ancient than the
mahabharata
it is closer to the time of the vedas
than the mahabharata is
so in the ramayana we have this very
clear episode in which lord rama
shoots a deer so it's not just for the
skin
i mean you don't waste what you what you
kill you have to eat it too
so it's clear that that lord rama was a
warrior
he was a so-called we call them
chatriers right
the warriors so he was a warrior and he
was definitely
someone who ate meat chatria's typically
have always had the tradition of
eating meat because warriors need to
have stronger bodies you need protein
you do get protein from plant sources
but it's much more readily available
if you eat meat on a regular basis so
meat eating wasn't was definitely
something that was not considered great
but it was not frowned upon that much
even the great um even uh
siddhartha gautam the lord buddha his
last meal is known to have been a dish
of
most likely pork in the city of
kushinagar in uh
north in in in
up or bihar somewhere thereabouts that
was his last meal
it was it was a dish of pork so indians
have always eaten meat
it has always been regarded to be the
highest morality not to eat
meat but that's what people who are not
engaged in martial professions
that's what they would do they would
refrain from eating meat but warriors
and people in
laborious professions etc usually did
eat meat so there is no such
tradition that ancient hindus did not
eat meat at all that's not the case
chetan asks what lies below the taj
mahal
and why have the doors been closed by
wall and does the taj mahal have a
secret way to the red fort
which is two kilometers from there so i
saw a video
by praveen mohan in which he shows that
there is a portion of the taj mahal
below the
main building which has been locked
off by the asi and there is clearly a
passageway inside
and i think it it it stretches back as a
considerable distance maybe two or three
kilometers
so there are definitely aspect aspects
of this building that have been hidden
off
that have been cut off from the people
there are other people are not allowed
to investigate
so so there is definitely a mystery
there and there is something that the
asi the archaeological survey of india
is hiding there is something they know
and there is something they don't want
the people of india to know about it
so i personally haven't been there i've
never had any interest in that in that
structure
and i have not visited it i have not
seen it so i cannot personally answer
what is there
what i can say is that there is
something hidden there and there is
something being deliberately hidden by
the asi
so i think it is time for see the asi is
an institution an organization that is
supposed to safeguard
the country's heritage on our behalf it
is our heritage they don't own the
heritage
they don't own the taj mahal they are
simply in charge of safeguarding it and
preserving it
and other other monuments on the behalf
of the people of india so the people of
india
are the true custodians of this heritage
the asi is simply
a public servant a public service it is
doing this work on our behalf
they cannot cordon off areas of ancient
monuments
and try to keep information away from us
it is time the asi is reformed
i think the asi should actually be
disbanded it is a corrupt and useless
organization
and a new body of professional
archaeologists
need needs to be put in place instead of
the ins in place of the asi
the asi has been overseeing the
wholesale loot and destruction
of india's heritage you hear stories in
the media you see news reports
every week of idols being stolen from
temples
idols being turning up in the west it's
a wholesale
pillage that's been going on since
colonial times
the asi is a colonial institution right
it was a
it was started by the british it was
started to
document india's ancient priceless
heritage and the asi
facilitated the transfer of ancient
indian
artwork and sculptures and priceless
items to the west
if you see the museums of the uk they
are full of stolen
indian heritage it was all facilitated
by the asi
and even today the asia is doing nothing
more than that they are
either negligent in the duty and temples
and
other monuments that are under their
jurisdiction
are being pillaged openly and nothing is
being done but of course they will
preserve the mughal monuments
very well and they will cordon off areas
of the taj mahal and not allow the
people to know what's there
so i think it's high time very either
reform this
useless organization or just get rid of
it and replace it with a
professional competent body that
actually
serves the nation and not doesn't serve
some other agenda
so it's high time we do this
okay om dikshit asks if indians lived
mostly topless in the ancient times due
to hot weather conditions
so why do we have an episode of the
draupadi vastra in mahabharata
okay so yeah
from the evidence that we have in
paintings in
ancient carvings and sculptures of our
ancestors
we see that both men and women were
mostly
topless in their daily lives they would
sometimes wear some light clothing
on the upper half of the body but mostly
they were topless and there was nothing
unusual about it today it would be very
unusual for either a male or a female to
go out anywhere topless it is
not acceptable in today's society in our
ancient pre-invasion preoccupation
society
it was perfectly normal it was nothing
unusual
so yes i did say that to the most extent
from the evidence we have
it appears that this was the case
because of the climatic conditions
so the clothing they wore was suitable
to the climate
but i never said that they were
bottomless i never said that
they went around naked right so vastra
can be something you wear on the bottom
as well
uh you know so so my point is the dropa
divastra heron means she was wearing
vastura i'm not saying i don't know what
she was wearing
maybe she was wearing a full dress or
maybe only the bottom part or whatever i
don't know i cannot speculate
the point is she was wearing vastra but
vastur can be
on the bottom part too right vastra
means clothing
so this episode of draupadi haran tells
you that
we our ancestors did wear clothing it
just doesn't mean they were completely
naked
if they did not wear a top it means that
maybe
most likely they wore something on the
bottom part something very ornate and
and uh good so
that's the reason why you had dropper
devastating because people
did wear vastra it's just that the top
part was left
mostly bare most times at most times
okay abraham asks due to colonization of
india by
and invasion by foreigners many facts
about our indian culture have been
hidden from us yes
and nowadays one of these topics which
is quite controversial and
debatable is homosexuality in india can
you tell us about this
as many say it's a thing brought
into india by foreigners and some say
that actually india was quite liberal
about it and it was not considered taboo
in indian culture
so here's what we know homosexuality
exists
a certain percentage of the population
tends to be like that so it is a natural
thing
there's something unnatural about it
it's a small minority of the overall
population but it does exist
and during india's colonial time
during the turkic occupation time as
well i am sure that homosexuality was
a crime when the british came here and
they
created their laws which india still
follows well they
they criminalized homosexuality and
until
just three or four years ago that law
was still in place so that colonial law
from the 19th century or thereabouts
was in force in india until two or three
years ago or
less than a decade ago so homosexuality
was criminalized in india
during the turkic era because of their
laws which we know very well
and the european christian morality
which came in with the british
so these abrahamic moralities and and
cultures they regard
homosexuality as a great sin and it is
usually punishable by death
now in ancient india we know that we had
see if you look at the pre-invasion the
preoccupation texts of india which are
extremely extensive and voluminous we
have extensive
indian literature that dates back
thousands of years so homosexuality
is not mentioned in that but
it is also not mentioned that
homosexuality should be criminalized or
penalized in any way
which means that homosexuals would have
existed
and they were not really taken notice of
or whatever i mean let it be
there was nothing written about them so
it was basically
uh from the evidence that we have the
evidence of absence
it looks like homosexuality was treated
with basically indifference
it didn't matter we do know that
transsexuals
have had a long history in india uh in
the mahabharat there was this
person called shikhandi who was born a
boy but was a girl or the other way
around i'm not really sure right now but
uh
it's one of the two things so this was a
transgender person
a great warrior right and a person of
great importance of of of at least a
certain significance
in this great ancient war that happened
in india and this person was well
respected right a trans
transgender person so transgenders have
been around for a long time and they
have never been
in any way marginalized or oppressed in
recent times
in the past thousand years or so
transgenders have been
oppressed and marginalized but today at
least you will see that in hinduism it's
not the case
in the kumbha mela you have the kinner
akada who are given the same rights and
same
same honor as every other akhada right
so it's clear that in indian culture
in the pre-invasion preoccupation
culture there was nothing in of any kind
against
transsexuals transgenders or homosexuals
because see we know now that hinduism is
greatly demonized nowadays
historians and sociologists and marxist
authors etc
they try and dig through indian texts
and find evidences of
something that is apparently bad today
and they
then they'd shout about from the
rooftops and i
guarantee that they've been trying to
find something about against homosexuals
in in
india's texts and they have found
nothing so that tells you that
homosexuals
may have been treated with indifference
in india but they were never oppressed
in any way or any form whatsoever
so so that is one thing which we can say
for sure about indian culture
that india was very liberal about
sexuality first of all
uh and and
i think homosexuality of any form is not
mentioned at all in
vatsayanas kamasutra etc
so india was very liberal about
sexuality and homosexuality seems to
have been treated with indifference
but there is absolutely not one
not the slightest shred of any evidence
that homosexuals
were oppressed or marginalized
or penalized in any way whatsoever in
ancient india in indian culture
okay the mahabharata war happened to be
a big event of killing just like a world
war
is there any sudden dip in population
count some millennia ago
good question right so this is this
great war this epochal event that
happened this apocalyptic war
that happened in ancient india so is
there any deep in population
here's the thing this war happened on a
battlefield
called kurukshetra it's in haryana today
it was fought
between two armies and there were rules
that both armies followed this was
basically the fighting started at
daybreak and it ended
at sunset there was no fighting between
daybreak and sunset
yes there were some crimes that the
korah was committed like killing the
sons of the pandavas etc but overall
this was a very well organized war it
was fought within
a framework of rules these rules were to
the most part not broken
and no non-combatant was harmed in this
war not one civilian was harmed in this
war
it was not a war that that destroyed
cities and villages and towns and all
that
it was a war that was localized to one
battlefield only that was the agreement
and that's how the entire 18 days of
this war
proceeded and not one bystander was
killed
you could stand outside the battlefield
and watch the proceedings of the war
as a civilian as a non-combatant and
nobody would
harm you so that is the way indians used
to go to war that's the kind of warfare
you had you had ethics and morality of
warfare
and that is what our ancestors tried to
use against
the turkic invaders and that's why india
got got
basically subjugated because the turks
had no ethics or morality of warfare
the only objective was to win the only
objective was victory
so the moral of the story is you can
fight in a civilized manner only when
your opponent is equally civilized
when your op your when your opponent is
not civilized when it does not recognize
the ethics and morality morality of
warfare that you do then you have to
fight according to his terms
so that is the the moral of that story
but as far as the mahabharata goes there
was no civilian casualties at
all no civilian was harmed no town no
village no city was destroyed
it only happened on one battlefield and
that's where the entire 18 days of the
war
uh unfolded so there is no deeper
population at
all not one civilian casualty
that's the thing
prabhav asks prabhav asks in the world
history episode you said the turkic
invasions and occupation of india
resulted in 500 million deaths but the
historian ks lal in one of his works
estimated that 60 to 80 million people
lost their lives due to wars
famines and massacres this is slightly
confusing can you please explain
all right good question good question
so the thing is no no historian has
actually done a proper analysis of how
many people died
during the turkic invasions so any
figures any numbers that anybody
including me gives
are at best educated guesses
right so we know that the british
occupied india for
about two and a half centuries right
and we know that they killed at least
100 million
indians at least so
in two centuries let's let's make it
easier to calculate
two centuries 100 million deaths just to
keep it simple
roughly it means half a million people
in it means half a million people uh
per per per year is it 200 years
100 so in one century 50 million people
so every year it's 5 million people half
a million
so if there is the death toll of half a
million people per year
then in two centuries you will have 100
million deaths okay so
i think the turks were much more brutal
than the british
but even if we were to apply the same
kind of mathematics to the turkic
occupation
and you had let's say five centuries
then that comes to at least 250 million
deaths deaths by starvation
and we know that there were lots of
families during the turkic times as well
and then you had the wholesale
slaughters and massacres etc
so i would actually give the figure of
about a hundred about one million deaths
per year of the turkic occupation across
the entire
geography of india which is an entire
subcontinent so that figure of one
million deaths per year
is actually quite conservative
given the brutality of the turks and the
in the kind of
massacres that they have recorded i mean
their historians
and chroniclers have gleefully recorded
the kind of atrocities they perpetrated
so if you give what if you assume the
figure of one million deaths
per year and they were in power for over
five centuries
then it gives you a figure of 500
million so this is an educated
guess it's an estimate nobody has tried
to
properly uh try and reconstruct the
events
but i think 500 million itself is a
conservative estimate
i think there could have been more and
you would say that how is it possible
500 million
india's population was 300 million at a
given time
i am talking about the cumulative death
toll of five centuries
or more right so even if one person died
one million people died per year over
500 million a year
500 years you have 500 million deaths so
that is the kind of
rough guesswork you have to do because
there are no official figures available
but we know that this is the worst
genocide ever perpetrated in the history
of humanity
this is what we know so that's how i
arrived at this rough
estimate of 500 million deaths i think
this is a conservative estimate i think
the actual number would exceed
500 million deaths over the entire
period of the turkic
invasions and occupation of india which
initially started around 700
ce and continued until the 16th century
and
further so i think 500 million is
actually
an underestimate
okay eisen says as a southern indian
hindi is an absolute alien language
there is a situation for a lot of people
in many indian states
however sanskrit is a language that
exists and is part of the language and
culture in every corner of india
the reason why the people of
much of southern india can't understand
hindi
is because hindi is so arabized and
urduized
the original hindi language
was sanskritized and that is a language
that is easily understandable to many
people
or most people in much of southern india
the tamil language this beautiful
ancient language
has a great deal of sanskrit in it right
we know that i have i've spoken about
this so many times
kannada has a great deal of sanskrit
telugu has a great deal of sanskrit
vocabulary malayalam has a great deal of
sense of vocabulary
every indian language is infused with
sanskrit vocabulary
this is undeniable and this is not some
colonial oppression or some
sanskritization
it's just what happened over thousands
of years of indian history
the harmonious intermingling of various
languages
and it's the same culture and same
civilization so it's bound to happen
and that the fact is that sanskrit is
not a dead language
you know people tell you sanskrit is a
dead language no it's not latin
is a dead language sanskrit is a living
breathing
language let me illustrate this
that the truth is that sanskrit is part
of every indian language
even today it's part of the vocabulary
and when you replace
mundane words with sanskrit words it
actually elevates
the language it elevates the discourse
so let me give you an example
let's say i say a sentence in hindi
now let's say i replace certain words
with sanskrit
with better sanskrit terms then i can
say aaj prata
menek shweth swan dekha so it doesn't
break the language
you still understand what i'm saying it
elevates the quality
of the discourse it elevates the
language
so sanskrit is very much alive you can
do the same thing
in any other indian language you can do
it in gujarati in marathi in
in kashmiri in assamese in oria
i'm sure you can do the same in tamil as
well in other southern indian languages
so sanskrit is very much a living
breathing part of our vocabulary
it actually elevates and civilizes our
discourse when we use
better sanskrit terms and if you do the
same thing
with latin in english or french
it's going to immediately break break
the language you won't understand what
you what what you're saying
so let me illustrate that too if i may
be permitted to do that let me
go to google translate
so let me translate from english to
latin
morning white
and dog i'll translate to latin so
morning is mani
white is album and dog is kanes so can i
say that today mane i saw an album kanis
you won't understand what i'm saying it
completely destroys the language it's
it's no longer a coherent speech the
same thing happens in french
if you use these words in french the
french word for morning is mata
white is blonde and dog is shia if you
use these three words instead of that it
breaks the language
you have no idea what the person is
saying that's why latin is a dead
language you can't do the same thing
with latin
that you can do with sanskrit so that
tells you that sanskrit is very much a
part of our
living breathing languages it's part of
our daily life it's part of our culture
and our civilization
and the reason hindi is not understood
is because it's been so badly arabized
and urdu
if it is brought back to its roots
everyone will understand it
but it's better that sanskrit should be
the civilizational language the one
language that binds this
ancient and great civilization together
once again
so this is a great observation that i
found
this is by anmol bhatia there's no doubt
that india and persia are the same
people they used to have the same
vedic customs but between cyruses and
darius's reign it all changed
and the asuras ahura mazda and the devas
they was evil ahura was the good they
was evil
so we know became opposite in the
culture with the rise of zoroaster
what's the reason for this sudden
cultural shift
so like i have said yes very good
observations and mold
so like i have said in previous episodes
the persians
are the parshwa people they are the
descendants of the parshwa clan
of the rig vedic indians there was this
great battle the battle battle of the
ten kings
and a great deal of a great many of
these clans were exiled
they lost the battle they were thrown
out of india they were exiled westwards
and northwards so the parsha people went
and settled in
present-day persia the land persia is
derived from that word parshwa
so like you say there's no doubt that we
are the same people
uh and these people were hindus i mean
if you call
that religion and culture of that time
hinduism then these
original portions were hindus and that
and then at some time this change
happened
it happened because of the rise of this
this one person zoroaster
his name was
in sanskrit and zarath means either
yellow or old
so zarathustra means a guy who has
either an old camel
or a golden camel okay so zarathustra
um he is the first known prophet of
humanity
and zoroastrianism is the first revealed
religion so he claimed that he
had a revelation from the great god
ahura mazda
and he revealed these this new religion
which was basically an inversion of
hinduism so the devas became evil
and the asuras or ahuras became good so
in zoroastrian
in zoroastrianism the morality is
inverted basic the morality is the same
but the
rules are inverted so in hinduism the
asuras are considered to be
somewhat evil somewhat on the
on the wrong side of good and evil and
the devas are the ones who are virtuous
so in zoroastrianism they inverted this
so this was essentially a rebellion
against the
ancestral culture against the old hindu
practices
so this is a genuine example
of what a rebellion against hinduism
looks like buddhism is not a
rebellion of any kind against hinduism
zoroastrianism is
so they inverted the roles of the devas
and the
asuras so that's what happened so this
happened
we don't know exactly when zarathustra
was alive
we don't know when he was born it was
somewhere before 1000 bce
maybe at the very dawn of the manish
dynasty that a cabinet
dynasty and uh
cyrus darya's were all zoroastrian
zoroastrians
they wrote about in their inscriptions
the
greatness of ahura mazda etc
so the reason for this cultural shift is
the emergence of zoroaster of
zarathustra and
for some reason his teachings
and preachings were for some reason
adopted very widely
we don't know what happened it's all
lost in the midst of time
i think zarathustra was born in bahalika
bulk
perhaps present day afghanistan that
time western india
so we don't know what caused this to be
so quickly widely adopted throughout the
parshwa region but it happened
and so the roles were inverted and that
zoroastrianism even though it has the
same traditions
the same language and the same origins
as
the other vedic customs it was actually
an attempt an act of rebelling against
the old
against the old ancestral culture of the
parsha people
so that's what we know about it zero
austrians zero austrian people today
exist mostly in india right some
do live in persia but they are very
badly uh oppressed and marginalized so
they had to escape to india
so it was a long journey full circle
they came back to the land of their
origin
and that's where these the majority of
parsees or zoroastrianism zoroastrians
still live today
so it's an interesting episode
of our ancient shared history between
india and persia
akash writes while re-reading the
history of the jaats
i come across statements like the jut
people are considered as the merged
descendants of indo-audience in those
keithian tribes of the region
merging to form the jaat people they are
known as goths in germany which was a
tribe that defeated the romans
this is basically stating that jaats are
aryans and it's false
the audient migration theory is a sham
so basically what you're asking
is what is the origin of the jacks and
where they always in
india excellent question
so let's start at the very beginning at
the very beginning all the rig vedic
clans were in india then you had the
battle of the 10 kings in which
the the losing coalition
all of the clans were expelled out of
india they had to run for their lives
so they went westwards they went
northwards they
and then the regions of uttarakuru and
uttara madra were formed
which were named after kuru and mudra
regions of india which is
the ganga yamuna region which is kuru
and the madra which is west of that
so uttarakuru and uptramadra were named
after these ancestral regions of these
exiled rigvedic clans
and later on these people these exiled
clans they established great kingdoms
in central asia the whole of central
asia was indian it was indianized
they spoke indian sanskrit derived
languages
and most likely these are the ancestors
of today's europeans the ones who spread
westwards
in great invasions and these are also
the ancestors of the kittens
and the kushans who were also basically
see these kittens are represented in
artwork modern artwork as being
fair skinned european look looking skin
blonde haired or red haired right that's
how they're
presented in in popular artwork
but when you find scythian burials you
analyze the dna
you can tell their skin tone that hair
color etc
we know that they had light skin but not
white skin
so their skin tone would have been
similar to mine okay and they had
dark hair and brown eyes so they would
look like me i guess
see so that's what a typical schizen
looked like they were of indian origin
today they are called iranian peoples
but the iranians themselves are of
indian origin fyi
so these kitians they roamed the whole
of central asia the
great steps of central asia all the way
from eastern europe all the way into
present-day xinjiang so-called xinjiang
of china where the
kushans or the tokkarians lived
so it was a great expanse across eurasia
so these are indian origin peoples the
sketians were not one
homogeneous people they had their own
clans and subdivisions
they may even have had a number of
languages
and one of these sketian
clans was called the masakate
the greek historian herodotus from the
5th century or 6th century bce
he wrote about this clan called the they
are the mahajats
okay so these are people who had gone
out of india
and they were their homeland was east of
the caspian sea
so it was the region of uh north of iran
and
parts of present-day afghanistan and
they entered into conflict with
the akka-minute dynasty the haksha
manish dynasty of iran
and they had a great queen called
thumbri
in greek they called her tomiris and
she fought a great battle with the
persian king
kurosh cyrus cyrus the great it was a
terrible battle
the worst the most terrible battle the
greeks had ever seen
and she killed cyrus the great and
took his head took his head with her in
retaliation for his killing her son
so these are the masakate or the
mahajats
and they went westwards and uh
they in in in europe they were called
the the goths
and the visigoths and the ostrogoths
so these are the people who who actually
sacked rome at one time
so there is this ethnic and cultural
continuum
that connects europe and in
parts of asia all the way up to india
and
so these masagate or mahajats are
connected to the jutt people of india
the jut people in india are are spread
across
many states mostly uh to a significant
extent in punjab haryana
but also in western up parts of
rajasthan et cetera it's a very
large geographical extent so the
masakate or the mahajat
this skitian clan or tribe where an
extension of the indian
jat people it is not known whether they
came into india and
reunited with the indian judge or not
but it is the same people
and the same people their descendants
are still found in europe and there is a
great similarity in names also
of the jet people and people in certain
parts of europe especially
germany right so i will uh
refer to you refer you to a very good
article
about about this topic let me share that
on the screen
so here it is the article is called
uttarakuru and the juts it's by dr
subhash
i highly recommend you read this article
it gives it gives a great deal of
information about this very specific
question very interesting article and
you should read more about doctors
by more articles by dr who is a
wonderful scholar
so that is the answer in brief to this
question
it's a very long roundabout story but
the jaats are basically indians
and they are closely connected to the
mahajats or the masakate
clan of the skittian people who were
also an indian people
indian origin and they are connected to
the ostrogoths and the visigoths
and various germanic people as well
so it's the same ethnicity and ancestry
overall
very interesting story
okay meenakshi asks the chola dynasty
had a huge and powerful navy
also indians were great seafarers and
they
predate the maratha empire by thousands
of years absolutely right yes
then why is chatrapati shivaji maharaja
called the father of the indian navy
and not rajendra chula or people below
him because titles do attract attention
which may motivate people to learn more
about these lost legends
i think you've got a good point here i
think the reason why
the emperor of the great emperor shivaji
maharaj is called the father of the
indian navy
is because he is the most recent great
king of india the most recent emperor
who used naval power in
military warfare and very effectively
and
with great success so he's the latest
and the most recent of our great kings
and emperors
who has done that and that's why he is
remembered as the father of the indian
navy
even though today's indian naval
tradition is entirely colonial
it is not from the time of the marathas
even then we remember the great shivaji
maharaj
as the father of the indian navy but
like you said
the cholas rajendra chola rajaraj they
had an even bigger
navy they conquered enormous maritime
empires they conquered the
entirety of southeast asia with their
naval power so they must have had a
formidable navy
the greatest navy of its time so i would
say that you have a good point here
and i think we should appoint sri
rajendra chola
as the grandfather of the indian navy
and we should consider the vedic
maritime people as the ancestors of the
indian navy
we are all basically part of the same
great tradition
we should definitely uh recognize the
incredible role
of rajendra chola and the cholas in in
continuing india's great maritime
tradition so yes
they definitely should be remembered but
the last
great emperor of india who used naval
warfare
effectively and with great success was
shivaji maharaja and that's why he is
called
the father of the indian navy so i would
not want to take the title away from him
we should call the cholas rajinder et
cetera the grandfathers of india's navy
and we should try and remember all of
our great naval
traditions all our military traditions
they are all equally important
and one would not have been possible
without the one that came before it
so they are all important and it is it
is
good for us it will be fruitful for us
for us to remember and recognize all of
these
great uh events and
chapters of our history
so with that i will end the uh
these questions let me take some live
questions i'm sure you're asking me some
so let me take a look
at your live questions now
let me try and find some interesting
questions
balaji subramaniam says ostrogoths
visigoths the gothic kingdoms have
origin in gothia
in mirrored lower made lower sweden the
gateish
kingdom have relations with the gods the
gods were used against huns by ones by
the romans it's a
complicated and fraught history gothea
in mid lower sweden also originated
somewhere else
what what evidence do we have the
whiskey gods and the ostrogoths
originated in gothia
there is no evidence of that these are
see these are people who came around
by migrations look at the islands for
example the islands are the people who
who are the ancestors of the spanish
iberian peoples
the islands were once iranian people
right they were called iranians or
aryans allans were aryans
because the iranians were the first
peoples to officially call themselves of
aryan ethnicity
and so on so the gods also are an
ancient offshoot of the masagatai
the sketian clan and later on they may
have moved on to various parts of europe
and today the eurocentric history will
say that they
originated in some region of europe but
if you look at the entirety
of history the past 5000 years the story
will tell you something else
it's the same thing like the step origin
of indo-iranian dna so it is said that
there was a region in the
central asian step from which uh various
invasions happened
east and west and that's how the
uh so-called indo-aryan peoples indo
indo-european peoples were popular
regions were populated
my question is where did they come from
before they reached the step
so you have to trace back the story to
its real origin right to its railroads
i know it all starts back in africa 70
000 years ago or so
but after that what happened the story
is only told in
slices we have to see the entirety of
the story to get a proper
understanding of what really happened so
yes they may have had some connection
with gauthia possibly
and they have had a fraught relationship
with the romans
they sacked rome they also were used by
the romans at a later time or
earlier time but they originated
with these kitten masakate
right
okay vivek sinha
what are some timeline gaps
spanned across centuries present in
indian history
similar to the bronze age collapse which
historians are still baffled with
we we have a reasonably okay
understanding of the last 1000 years of
our history
there are still certain kingdoms and
dynasties which are not known or are are
not written about spoken about but we
have a reasonably good idea of the
past 1200 years or so of india's history
the gupta age is not that well
understood the
the time of the rashtrakuta the gurjar
pratihars
the the maha chatrapas
etc that time is not very well
understood there are some gaps in our
understanding of that time
the gupta age is also not entirely well
understood
then there is this gap when we don't
know when our historians say that
king vikramaditya was a mythical king he
did not even exist which is absolute
nonsense
so there are significant gaps as we go
further back in time
there was a time when we did not know
when king when emperor kanishka was was
in power when he was alive today we seem
to have a reasonably good understanding
of
of his time period and then we know that
the time period of the buddha about 500
bce or thereabouts we know about the
modern age the
the shonga age but we we have absolutely
no data from before the time of the
buddha in mahavira
so the buddha and mahavira are supposed
to be contemporaries of each other
more or less similar time period but
what came before that
there's an enormous gap it's like there
was no indian history at all
before the buddha so that's how that's
what you find in
every official history of india in any
textbook
it all starts with the buddha then the
mauryas etc
and it's like there was nothing before
the buddha at all there was no history
in india
before the buddha but we know there was
an enormous amount of history in india
before the buddha
we know it from archaeology this entire
sindhu region the harappan the saraswati
indus river basins there is so much
there which clearly predates the buddha
by a great deal
and the history of varanasi and other
places also is very ancient
partly butra also seems to be a very
ancient city
present-day patna so we know absolutely
nothing about
what happened before the buddha we have
archaeological evidence that a great
deal of things
that great amount of history is unknown
to us
but we don't know the names of those
cities we don't know the names of the
kings
and people who lived there who ruled
there we don't know the names of the
great people
who did great deeds there and yet we
have this very ancient history
from the vedas and the great epics so
there are enormous
gaps in the timeline of timeline of
indian history
there are partial gaps between between
the time of the buddha
and about 1 000 years ago many partial
gaps
but the real yawning chasm is the time
before
the buddha and that's where our
historians have fallen flat they have
not
bothered to try and piece together the
timeline of our history
before that and the truth is that our
ancient literature does talk about
entire lineages of kings that came much
before the buddha and all
so it is i think it would be very uh
worthwhile
to take that very seriously these are
ancient records these are not myths
and try and piece together time that the
timeline from various records
and try and correlate that with the
various archaeological findings
whether we can find some one-to-one
correspondence and then
we can start piecing together our
history
so the answer is there are many gaps
many enormous gaps
okay let me take a look
at some more questions
so divyang asks what is the best known
chronology of indian literature ramayana
is older than mahabharata
veda upanishad etc so the vedas are the
oldest literature
uh the vedas are clearly the oldest
literature the samhitas etc are texts
that are attached to the vedas
the puranas are so
the vedas are known as shruti i think
the shruti literature which is
taken as canonical literature literature
whose
validity is unquestioned and then you
have qurans which are which are smriti i
think smriti literature
or secondary literature or derived
literature
and then there are commentaries like
upanishads etc i am not entirely
100 clear about the entirety of this
because it's very complicated so maybe i
can check it out again and revisit this
question
the next time we know the ramayana is
definitely older than the mahabharata
so we had the vedas written at a very
very ancient time
at the very beginning of you could say
indian civilization
then you had the ramayana then you had
the mahabharat
and and so on so you had late vedic
texts you had early vedic texts you have
four
vedas etc and then you had text that are
still vedic but that
that post date the with the four vedas
also
so it's an extremely complex situation
there are tens of thousands of very
valuable
texts so i think i i need to
maybe make a separate video about this
and explain all this in detail
because if i give you some answers right
now i may end up misplacing
something somewhere you know so i think
i'll make a separate video about this
and explain this in detail so that i'll
put that on my to-do list
but that is the overall chronology of
the
major components of india's literature
so that's a good question thank you for
that
who was samira miss sami that was a
queen of
uh somewhere in in mesopotamia
at least three thousand years before
today
and it is said that she had some she she
had some she entered into a conflict
with an indian king as well
i am not entirely conversant with that
story it's a minor story in
as far as i'm concerned but if you want
i can look it up i don't know about the
20 horses i think she's mentioned in
biblical literature as well
and maybe she was possibly the first
female monarch of that region
it's an interesting story i don't
remember everything right now so
i will look it up and i'll get back to
you about that that's a very interesting
question actually
so let me get back to you the next time
and answer this question
so shirish i have answered this question
before as well
we don't have absolute evidence
of whether they were indians or not it
there is circumstantial evidence
that seems to show some parallels in
culture
and other things between india and the
ancient americas but we don't have any
actual hard evidence as of today so
maybe in the future
we may find something but as of today we
have to say we don't know
this is by sudan singh hello sir uh
any history of slavery and harams in
indian subcontinent under hindu kings i
can answer in one word
no no slavery no harams
indian kings did have multiple wives
polygamy was
accepted in hinduism so was polyandry
fyi
there was no slavery whatsoever multiple
foreign sources have attested the fact
that indians did not ever keep slaves
so today the marxist historians tried to
conflate the word
dasa with the term slave
dasa was not slave dasa was originally
an ethnic group
later it was this term became
synonymous with the position of a
servant a servant is not a slave
a servant is somebody who serves who
serves
even the prime minister is a public
servant
every government official is a servant
of the public so dasa essentially means
servants
so that is the term they have tried to
conflate with slavery which is
completely
completely wrong so in short the answer
is there was no slavery in india and
there were never any harams
multiple marriages multiple wives were
indeed kept by many
indian kings which is not the same as a
harem a harem is a
confined zoo of the female species
which are used for a certain perverse
purpose
that is what was done in the middle east
and with certain cultures
it was never the case in india ever
women had the highest of
respect and dignity in indian culture so
very good question sir and the answer is
no and no
okay let me take two more questions
because it's been already 90 minutes
okay let me take this one by paris negi
what is the age-old relation between
india and china
there is even the mention of a region of
china and mahabharata okay there is the
mention of a region called china
during the mahabharata year now how do
we know that
china of the mahabharata time is china
of today
china is an english word the chinese
call themselves their country
rongwo they don't say china
this term china is an english word it's
a it's a
it's a it's an exonym it's a name given
to this country
by foreigners the same way that india is
not an indian word
we call ourselves either bharat or
aryawath or jambudweep
india is a foreign term similarly china
is a foreign term
japan is a foreign term for nippon or
nihon
etc so the china people the china tribe
of the mahabharat is a different tribe
there is no relationship between that
and the chinese
chinese civilization is about two and a
half or three thousand years old
at the very most the mahabharata
happened many thousands of years before
that
from the best evidence that we have
so they are not equally old india and
chinese civilization
chinese civilization is a very recent
phenomenon india civilization is at
least ten thousand years old at the very
least
so there was no mention of china
zhongguo
in the mahabharata there was the mention
of a tribe called the china people
which had nothing to do with the chinese
with the modern chinese
so i hope that clarifies this this
question i get a lot of this question so
thanks for asking it
one last question is it true that
maharaja ranjit singh's flag had hindu
goddess
and anumanji as the symbol if yes then
why are six nowadays so much averted by
the hindu ancestry
let me answer the first part of the
question yes absolutely
maharaja ranjit singh's flag was a
saffron flag
it had the goddess durga
and hanumanji as well on the flag that
was the symbol
mostly it was goddess durga on the
saffron flag
so that was the flag of maharaja ranjit
singh
and maharaja ranjit singh forbade
cow slaughter and every other turkic
practice that was
offensive to indian culture and the
ancient
the the sikh gurus of old were basically
hindus they considered themselves hindus
only
even guru nanak has said this nowadays
why is sikhism
averting itself from hinduism well
that's a question of politics
it's very recent politics i will i
deal with history let the politics be
dealt with the politicians
that is a matter of recent history
recent history is very well known to us
so i don't think i need to go into that
it's something that
needs to be addressed definitely sikhism
is very much part of the dharmic
umbrella it's always been
they are very much part of indian
civilization indian culture
they are the same people as us so what's
what's happening nowadays
is unfortunate and
i think it is it is the duty
of the government of india to address
with address these issues if they if
they are willing to
but like you said it is very much true
that maharaja ranjit singh
his flag had got his durga on it and i
think
some of his emblems also had hanumanji
on them
so that's the answer all right my
friends it's been a great session
95 minutes thank you for all the
wonderful questions
uh there are many more questions that i
have i am saving all your questions and
i will answer i'll keep answering
all of these so we'll keep conti we'll
continue doing this
and for today it's the end of this
session so i will see you in the next
episode
thank you very much have a great day
have a great night
bye